<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philip's Notebook</title>
    <description>Online residence of Philip C Davis</description>
    <link>http://philipcdavis.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://philipcdavis.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Making Wagon Pool</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I made my first app this past year. It’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wagonpool.com/&quot;&gt;simple carpooling calculator&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to find out how much a trip will cost each person involved.
I designed and built Wagon Pool from scratch without any previous Objective C, Xcode, or Object Oriented Programming experience.
While it’s still fresh in my mind I wanted to document the process I took in building it.
This post may be helpful for you if you want to learn how to make mobile applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-goals&quot;&gt;My Goals&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope for this project was to be able to ship something I was proud of.
I wanted the app to be simple, focused, and better than alternative options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to have a good understanding of what it takes to build an iOS application.
I needed to learn Object Oriented Programming and learn mobile development on its own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting Started:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a 99 cent notebook to help organize my thoughts. I sketched, illustrated, and diagrammed my way through the entire process.
This gave me extra mental space, and helped me visualize what was going on in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dist/posts/wagon-notepad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Notebook&quot; title=&quot;Notebook&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted the app to look polished and to make calculating easy.
I spent a lot of time thinking about how I wanted the users to input information.
I mocked up 8 different ways the interface could work.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dist/posts/wagon-mockups.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mockups&quot; title=&quot;Mockups&quot; /&gt;
I chose the last option as a starting point because the user can get fast estimates without having to type or switch pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started with something simple for the icon which I was planning on using.
A friend challenged me to make something memorable.
I sketched out lots of ideas some of which looked great at 512x512, but poor on the actual device.
After much tweaking I came up with something I liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dist/posts/wagon-icon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Icon&quot; title=&quot;Icon&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;development&quot;&gt;Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing Wagon Pool was both challenging and rewarding. So many hours went into such a small app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got comfortable with Xcode by creating outlets, using simple methods, and exploring interface builder. I created a working version in a short period of time, however there were serious flaws in my approach. For example, Everything was inside my view controller.
I knew that a lot of my code didn’t belong there, but I didn’t know where else to put it. There was also a lot of excess code that I needed to eliminate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/course/developing-ios-7-apps-for/id733644550&quot;&gt;Stanford course&lt;/a&gt; on iTunes University.
However, I realized I needed to get a stronger grasp on Object Oriented Programing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read Matt Neuburg’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/iOS-Programming-Fundamentals-Objective-C-Basics/dp/1491945575/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1409103316&amp;amp;sr=8-2&quot;&gt;iOS fundamentals&lt;/a&gt; front to back.
This was an invaluable investment. The first five chapters were especially helpful since they covered the fundamentals of iOS development.
At the same time, I was coding every night and putting into practice what I was learning. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I finished the book, there was still much to be done. I let myself go down rabbit holes to better understand MVC patterns, auto layout, delegation, and animation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ship-it&quot;&gt;Ship it&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About three months in I signed up for the iOS developer program.
I wanted to spend time debugging, learn about memory management, and get feedback.
I received a lot feedback and opinions. The biggest issue was that users didn’t have enough control over their input.
I decided to create a modal that gave users the ability to enter in values outside the default range.
This set me back a few weeks, but I’m glad I decided to address it in the v1.0 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;small&quot; src=&quot;/assets/dist/posts/wagon-glyphs.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a small app, but it’s something I am very proud of.
Check it out on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/wagon-pool-simple-carpooling/id846135212?mt=8&quot;&gt;app store&lt;/a&gt; and let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dist/posts/wagon-screenshots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshots&quot; title=&quot;Screenshots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;legal&quot;&gt;Apple, the Apple logo, iPhone, and iPod touch are trademarks of Apple Inc., registered in the U.S. and other countries. App Store is a service mark of Apple Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/making-wagonpool</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/making-wagonpool</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Become a Front End Developer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently taught a front end intensive course to people who had no coding experience.
Here are three thoughts I would share with new front end developers or those considering the profession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;technical-confidence&quot;&gt;Technical confidence.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting started it’s easy to feel overwhelmed.
It’s important to remember that a lot of front end developers are self taught.
If you are self motivated, and have time and energy to devote you can overcome the barriers to this field.
A great place to begin is with a solid understanding of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
Learning these will build your confidence and allow your to explore other languages, and frameworks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mental-grit&quot;&gt;Mental grit.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are moments in your work where you aren’t eager to learn new things.
&lt;a href=&quot;../Staying-Engaged/&quot;&gt;Staying engaged with your work&lt;/a&gt; is important for those getting started because it’s easier to drop out.
You need to position yourself so that you don’t get stuck for long.
Make sure your expectations are realistic enough to overcome the hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creative-outlets&quot;&gt;Creative Outlets.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the skills you are learning and put them to work.
Building and shipping is a great way to learn.
If you can’t do this at your job, create side projects.
You need to have creative drive that keeps you engaged and hungry to learn.
Devour resources and never stop exploring the terrain because it changes fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can capitalize on one of the most enjoyable professions around right now if you approach it with the right attitudes. 
You need the confidence that allows you undertake this education and the humility to know you will get stuck along the way.
Start with the essentials and keep creating new things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/How-To-Become-A-Front-End-Developer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/How-To-Become-A-Front-End-Developer</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Staying Engaged With Your Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There will always be seasons when you lose motivation to do your work with excellence.
When it happens, it means something needs to change, either in your attitude or in the work itself.
You have to stay engaged with your work to thrive in your career.
Here are some things that have helped me through droughts of motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-let-your-work-define-you&quot;&gt;Don’t let your work define you.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look to your job to provide meaning and significance it will let you down.
Your work is important, but it’s not your identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-a-side-project&quot;&gt;Create a side project.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side projects give you the freedom to define the rules and explore the things you want to learn.
I always have 1-2 side projects that relate to my work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;surround-yourself-with-passionate-people&quot;&gt;Surround yourself with passionate people&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are the average of the five people that you spend the most time with.
-  Jim Rohn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivation is contagious. Find people who love what they do and spend lots of time with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/philipcdavis&quot;&gt;How do you get out of your motivation ruts?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 17:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/Staying-Engaged</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/Staying-Engaged</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Art of Listening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years i’ve realized how much I dislike listening in one on one conversations and how much I enjoy attention.
This destructive tendency can jeopardize any relationship which is why I have been fighting it. 
I’ve learned a few things along the way that have helped me become a better listener. I hope they help you as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-genuinely-interested-in-people&quot;&gt;Be genuinely interested in people&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you really don’t care about a story or opinion.
It’s important to take interest in the person sharing them.
Caring for people allows me to enjoy stories that I don’t find exciting, or opinions that I am indifferent to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;follow-up-with-questions&quot;&gt;Follow up with questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following up is about asking relevant and helpful questions.
It can be very easy to kill a conversation. People know when their words aren’t appreciated.
I’ve found that asking questions is a more effective way of engaging others than offering advice or opinions.
Have them flesh out their thoughts or give examples.
It shows that you are engaged and allows meaningful conversational to take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-people-time&quot;&gt;Give people time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the best thoughts out of people, don’t pressure them to talk faster than they are comfortable with.
I am trying to wait for a minimum of 3-5 seconds of silence before I respond.
I used to feel awkward about this, But a quick nod fills this time and serves as a transition to a shift in conversation.
If you are talking with someone who wants to have 100% of the time to talk, be generous and give it to them.
Playing tug of war in a conversation makes for a frustrating experiance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoning out and interrupting will kill your conversations.
Appreciation and generosity will pump life into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/philipcdavis&quot;&gt;What are some of your listening tips?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 02:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://philipcdavis.com/Art-of-Listening/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://philipcdavis.com/Art-of-Listening/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beginning Again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed to redo my website for a lot of reasons. The most important being speed.
My previous website was awfully slow.
There were lots of reasons why that was, the most important being lots of huge uncompressed images.
There is still work to be done, but already the speed index has gone from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webpagetest.org/result/140602_PK_24V/&quot;&gt;9295&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webpagetest.org/result/140602_82_246/&quot;&gt;634&lt;/a&gt;.
Still working on making the reading experience optimal.
If you notice anything funky, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/philipcdavis/philipcdavis.github.io/issues&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/philipcdavis&quot;&gt;I would love to hear from you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 19:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/Beginning-Again</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/Beginning-Again</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
