<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philip's Notebook</title>
    <description>Online residence of Philip C Davis</description>
    <link>http://philipcdavis.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://philipcdavis.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Staying Engaged With Your Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There will always be seasons when you lose motivation in your work.
When it happens, it means something needs to change, either in your attitude or in the work itself.
You have to stay engaged with your work to thrive in your career.
Here are some things that have helped me through droughts of motivation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dont-let-your-work-define-you&quot;&gt;Don’t let your work define you.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look to your job to provide meaning and significance it will let you down.
Your work is important, but it’s not your identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;create-a-side-project&quot;&gt;Create a side project.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Side projects give you the freedom to define the rules and explore the things you want to learn.
I always have 1-2 side projects that relate to my work. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;surround-yourself-with-passionate-people&quot;&gt;Surround yourself with passionate people&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are the average of the five people that you spend the most time with.
-  Jim Rohn&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motivation is contagious. Find people who love what they do and spend lots of time with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/philipcdavis&quot;&gt;How do you get out of your motivation ruts?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 17:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/Staying-Engaged</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/Staying-Engaged</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Art of Listening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few years i’ve realized how much I dislike listening in one on one conversations and how much I enjoy attention.
This destructive tendency can jeopardize any relationship which is why I have been fighting it. 
I’ve learned a few things along the way that have helped me become a better listener. I hope they help you as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-genuinely-interested-in-people&quot;&gt;Be genuinely interested in people&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you really don’t care about a story or opinion.
It’s important to take interest in the person sharing them.
Caring for people allows me to enjoy stories that I don’t find exciting, or opinions that I am indifferent to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;follow-up-with-questions&quot;&gt;Follow up with questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following up is about asking relevant and helpful questions.
It can be very easy to kill a conversation. People know when their words aren’t appreciated.
I’ve found that asking questions is a more effective way of engaging others than offering advice or opinions.
Have them flesh out their thoughts or give examples.
It shows that you are engaged and allows meaningful conversational to take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-people-time&quot;&gt;Give people time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get the best thoughts out of people, don’t pressure them to talk faster than they are comfortable with.
I am trying to wait for a minimum of 3-5 seconds of silence before I respond.
I used to feel awkward about this, But a quick nod fills this time and serves as a transition to a shift in conversation.
If you are talking with someone who wants to have 100% of the time to talk, be generous and give it to them.
Playing tug of war in a conversation makes for a frustrating experiance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zoning out and interrupting will kill your conversations.
Appreciation and generosity will pump life into them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/philipcdavis&quot;&gt;What are some of your listening tips?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 02:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://philipcdavis.com/Art-of-Listening/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://philipcdavis.com/Art-of-Listening/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beginning Again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I needed to redo my website for a lot of reasons. The most important being speed.
My previous website was awfully slow.
There were lots of reasons why that was, the most important being lots of huge uncompressed images.
There is still work to be done, but already the speed index has gone from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webpagetest.org/result/140602_PK_24V/&quot;&gt;9295&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webpagetest.org/result/140602_82_246/&quot;&gt;634&lt;/a&gt;.
Still working on making the reading experience optimal.
If you notice anything funky, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/philipcdavis/philipcdavis.github.io/issues&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;feedback&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/philipcdavis&quot;&gt;I would love to hear from you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 19:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/Beginning-Again</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://philipcdavis.com/notebook/Beginning-Again</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
